it's the 13th of July in Butler
Pennsylvania former US president Donald
Trump speaks at a rally it's only days
until he plans to accept the official
Republican nomination he's just minutes
into his speech when shots are fired
take a look at what
[Music]
happened Trump got hit but survived
someone tried to assassinate him in
broad daylight here is how it
unfolded
Fern by the time this video is published
new details might have
emerged it's a hot sweltering early
evening as tens of thousands gather here
to see Trump Pennsylvania is one of six
vital swing States that will help secure
the win in the next presidential
election Butler skews heavily Republican
and it is a bluecar
town this is a big crowd this is a big
big beautiful
crowd he is surrounded by supporters
most are sitting or standing in front of
the stage some sit on the bleachers
Center left and right Trump's support
staff and security including Secret
Service agents are right at the stage
behind him are three large buildings on
the roof of the building on the far left
and on the far right are Secret Service
snipers they are constantly scanning the
surroundings looking for threats they
can be seen in this video filmed by a
crowd
member hello Butler and hello to
Pennsylvania I'm thrilled to be back
Trump begins with his speech things seem
normal he turns to the right and points
at a chart showing statistics on border
crossings at the same time time several
people in the crowd notice a man with a
gun on the roof of a building close by
he it's too late take a look what
happened all of a sudden bullets start
flying one even gets captured on
camera another building about 400 ft or
120 M north of the stage the shots are
coming from here on the
roof the gunman is 20-year-old Thomas
Matthew Kooks he is armed with an AR-15
semi-automatic rifle the gun was legally
purchased by his father first he
apparently fires around of three shots
take a look at what
happened Trump reaches up with his hand
the first bullet pierces the upper part
of his right ear he will later say that
turning over to the right at that exact
moment prevented the bullet from hitting
him right in the head he Ducks down
behind the podium and within 3 to 4
seconds after the first shot secret
service agent swarmed the former
president and Shield him with their
bodies Crooks opens fire again
immediately with five more
shots right before the first shot by
Crooks one of the snipers on the left
roof behind Trump seems to detect the
gunman and prepares to return fire take
a look at what
happened some Outlets report that these
snipers killed Crooks while the secret
service confirmed its Personnel
neutralize the shooter we could not
corroborate that it was in fact these
specific agents the gunmen also hit
spectators on the bleachers one man died
50-year-old Cory comprador two others
were critically injured with Trump's
microphone still on we can hear the
tense exchanges among the
agents on ready on you
Mo about 42 seconds after Crook's open
fire they confirm the shooter is
down we good Shooters down are we good
to move we clear we we're they prepare
to escort him to an armored
vehicle let me get my let me get my I
got you sir I got you sir let me get my
shoes hold that in your head bloody so
we got to move to the to the let me get
myo
okay watch
out wait wait wait in about 75 seconds
after ducking to the ground Trump raises
his fist he's mouthing the words fight
fight fight the resulting photo
immediately travel around the entire
world the crowd starts to Champ for the
former president as he leaves the stage
leeding Trump is then rushed to a
hospital later that night he has flown
to New Jersey he appears to be
well there are a lot of questions we
don't have an answer to right now why
were the forces unable to prevent the
attack
analysis on X suggests that at least the
snipers on the roof behind Trump were
likely Scouting For dangers further away
with this rooftop possibly falling into
the responsibility of other law
enforcement agents we were unable to
corroborate that why couldn't our men
climb up on this building what was
krook's motive the Gman had no criminal
history in Pennsylvania's public court
records the New York Times found a voter
registration record for Crooks it shows
that he was registered as a republican
they also found that he donated $15 to a
liberal voter turnout group through a
democratic donation platform in 2021 he
was a kitchen worker and had a
membership at a local shooting club the
FBI found suspicious devices in both his
car and home they are being evaluated by
the agency at the time of this recording
the investigation is ongoing and new
information is being published by the
minute President Biden and various
leaders around the world condemn the
attack and political violence at large
the picture of trump bloodied but
defiant with a raised fist in front of
the American flag will surely become a
powerful symbol in his re-election
campaign